

STEVE EARLE

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY GENERALIST

CONTACT

6043 Welsford Street, Apt. 2

Halifax, Nova Scotia, B3K 1G3

steve.earle.dev@gmail.com

https://steve-earle.github.io

1-902-219-2072

Steve Earle

[6043 Welsford Street, Apt. 2] [Halifax, Nova Scotia, B3K 1G3] [1-902-219-2072] [steve.earle.dev@gmail.com] [steve-earle.github.io]

Profile

I am an IT Generalist with a background in software development, full-stack web development, technical support, and customer service. A portfolio of my work can be found at https://steve-earle.github.io

Expertise

Software Development

Developing mobile and desktop applications with C, C++, C#, Java, and Python using object-oriented methodology

Web Development

Front and back-end web development with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP, Bootstrap, and Laravel

Database Administration

Querying, editing, and storing information in databases with SQL using SQLite

Version Control/Collaboration

Collaborating and controlling project code with **GitHub**

Project Management

Organizing software development with Scrum/Agile methodologies

Customer Service

Solving customer tickets using support software such as **Zendesk**

Transcription

Transcribing audio at 75 wpm

Steve Earle

[6043 Welsford Street, Apt. 2] [Halifax, Nova Scotia, B3K 1G3] [1-902-219-2072] [steve.earle.dev@gmail.com] [steve-earle.github.io]

Work Experience

Appen Limited

IT Contractor

May 2019 – Present

Halifax, Nova Scotia (working remotely)

Responsibilities:

- Management of multiple contracts providing data for machine learning algorithms, search engine evaluation, and mapping application accuracy analysis for telecommunications companies
- Recording and transcription services
- Invoice documentation

GDI Integrated Facility Services

Maintenance Contractor

June 2014 – January 2017

Halifax, Nova Scotia

Responsibilities:

- Management of multiple contracts for building maintenance and cleaning services
- On-site custodial services for offices and warehouse settings
- Maintaining positive client relations

Home Depot

Lot Attendant

May 2013 – April 2014

Dartmouth, Nova Scotia

Responsibilities:

- Assisting customers with product information, locating items, and the loading of heavy items
- General cleaning duties, maintaining a high standard of store cleanliness
- Garbage disposal and recycling
- Store display set-up (assembling furniture, tools, etc.)

Wal-Mart

Garden Center Associate

July 2011 – April 2013

Dartmouth, Nova Scotia

Responsibilities:

- Assisting customers with product information, locating items, and the loading of heavy items
- Watering and maintaining health of plants in the Garden Center
- Unloading and organization of new product, product facing
- Cashier duties

Steve Earle

[6043 Welsford Street, Apt. 2] [Halifax, Nova Scotia, B3K 1G3] [1-902-219-2072] [steve.earle.dev@gmail.com] [steve-earle.github.io]

Education

Nova Scotia Community College

IT Programming Diploma

September 2017 – May 2019

Classes completed:

- Logic and Programming (Python)
- Programming II (C)
- Introduction to Object-Oriented Programming (Java)
- Data Fundamentals (SQL)
- Transactional Database Programming (SQL)
- Operating Systems: Linux
- Introduction to Windows Administration
- Introduction to Networking and Security
- Introduction to Systems Analysis and Design
- User Interface Design and Development
- Website Development (HTML and CSS)
- Advanced Object-Oriented Programming (C#)
- Mobile Application Development for Android (Java and XML)
- Programming C++
- Project Management
- Web Application Programming (PHP)
- Special Topics (Zendesk, GitHub)

Skills

- Motivated problem-solver
- Productive independently or as a member of a team
- Personable communicator
- Easy going and hard working